# COREY JACKSON



SUDBURY, ONTARIO • 705-626-1433 • cjaxsn@gmail.com • https://coreyjackson.tech

#### **PROFILE**

A dynamic senior IT professional with over 20 years experience in information technology with focuses in management, project management, security, architecture, networking, systems analysis, integration, automation, development, quality assurance, & support in bothprivate and public sectors. My various experiences are summarized within this cv, however, a detailed listing of my experiences can be found on my online resume located at <a href="https://coreyjackson.tech">https://coreyjackson.tech</a>.

#### SOFT SKILLS

- Leadership, team building, decision making, mentoring, negotiation, and presentation skills
- Innovative, creative, responsible, cooperative, hard working, versatile, flexible, and adaptable
- Possess strong organizational, time management, conflict management, and analytical thinking skills
- Written and oral communication skills in English and French languages

## TECHNICAL / HARD SKILLS

Management: Strategic planning, department & product management, budgeting, performance management

Project Management: Agile, Waterfall, Scrum, Scheduling, Prioritization, JIRA, MS Project, Primavera

Architecture: TOGAF, SDLC, process mapping, data modeling, service oriented architecture (SOA)

Security: Vulnerability Management, Penetration Testing, Ethical Hacking, System Harderning, Information Security, Secure Application Development, Password Management, NIST 800-x, ISO 27001, PCI DSS, 2FA/MFA/U2F, OAuth, SSO, SAML, SSL/TLS, AES, PGP, CORS, CSRF, XSS, Email and Web Security Gateways, DLP, DMARC, Kali Linux, FileAudit Plus, Netwrix, Nmap, Nessus, Metasploit, Nikto

Cloud & Server Computing: IaaS, PaaS, Saas, AWS, Azure, Digital Ocean, Scale, VMWare, VirtualBox

DevOps: Bamboo, BitBucket, Git, SourceTree, TortoiseGit, Bash, Shell, PowerShell, Kubernetes

**Development Languages/Technologies:** .NET/Core, API's, Python, JSON, ASP,JSP,PHP, Perl, CSS, HTML, XML, AJAX, Bootstrap, jQuery, React, AngularJS, node.js, Java, JavaScript, Groovy, C#, Git, SPA, PWA

#### Data Applications/Technologies:

NoSQL - CouchDB, PouchDB, IndexedDB, MongoDB

RDBMS - MS SQL Server, MariaDB, MySQL, Oracle, SQLLite, ADO, DAO, ODBC, OLEDB, SQL

Data historians/products: AspenTech Setcim, OSISoft PI, PI-ACE, PI-AF, PI Batch, PI Coresight, PI-PE, DataLink, PI Manual Logger, ProcessBook, PI WebParts, Totalizers

OT/Process Control: SCADA, DCS, InFusion, Wonderware, Foxboro, PLCs, RSView, HMI's

**Networking:** WAN,LAN,VLAN,MESH,UTM,ASA,Firewalls,Routers,Gateways,Switches,Hubs,Bridges, Access Points, Print Servers, Proxies,VPN,DHCP,DNS,WINS,TCP/IP,IPSEC,IPS/IDS,ACLs,QoS, SSH, STP, NTP, SNMP, RADIUS, SIP, VOIP, SIEM, Satellite and Cellular comm, Cabling (CAT5/6), IP Cameras,FreePBX, SolSwitch, wireless network optimization, interior and exterior network installation

Networking Tools: inSSIDer, NetSpot, NetLimiter, PTRG, PuTTY, Nmap, Wireshark, tcpdump, iPerf

Web Servers and Remote Tools: Apache, NGINX, IIS, Tomcat, Team Viewer, Anydesk, VNC, RDP

Operating Systems: Linux, Unix, Mac OS, iOS, Android, Windows 3.xx-10/Server 2000-2016, VMS, DOS

Design/Estimating: UML, ERD, DFD, Visio, Draw.io, AutoCAD, Revit, SketchUp, Accubid, WinEst

Reporting: ActiveReports, Business Objects, Crystal Reports, Pentaho, Power BI, SSRS, SharePoint

# WORK EXPERIENCE

Sofvie Inc. 2019-2020

# **Product & Service Supervisor**

- Managed direct reports in various roles of product development and the agile project development plan
- Supervised direct reports in the support and service of customers and internal staff
- Supervised direct reports in continuous delivery and integration of products (DevOps)
- Managed best practices and standards in the product development of a secure risk management system
- Lead product quality assurance and implementation of automated testing framework
- Participated in product hosting strategy (cloud, on premise, hybrid)

# **TESC Contracting Company Ltd. & SWSE Athletic Teams**

2015-2019

## IT Manager

- Defined and implemented the IT strategic initiatives based upon the company's annual strategic business plan
- Defined company growth objectives in partnership with the business
- Built trusting relationships with key stakeholders serving as an advisor of technologies to improve effectiveness
- Defined technology roadmaps and overall technology vision
- Drove collaboration across multiple teams, business units and phases, aligning IT Systems with business operations
- Managed projects including the assessment of requirements, provisions of functional deliverables, milestone planning, project closure, and lessons learned
- Managed comprehensive IT portfolio and IT projects with direct reports and 3<sup>rd</sup> party resources
- Managed an IT helpdesk for 200 users utilizing ITIL framework for incident and problem management
- Defined and implemented the IT strategic initiatives based upon the company's annual strategic business plan
- Implemented cost saving solutions in IT and ares of business, new technologies, policies, procedures, and standards
- Managed IT infrastructure (servers, storage, backups, security systems), software, licenses, and contracts
- Implemented a security risk management framework including management, operational and physical security
- Managed the implementation of several key IT projects:
  - Digital transformation, global enterprise wireless network, standard video conferencing and collaboration system, inventory management systems (IT and specific business areas), safety management information system, company intranet, global VoIP system

Vale Canada Limited 2009-2015

# IT Subject Matter Expert / IT Project Manager

- Managed a team of developers including project budgets, schedules and training development
- Implemented best practices, standards, and product roadmaps for areas of expertise
- Managed the implementation of many IT projects such as: computerized mould tracking system, redundant data collection system from the Smelter process control network to business network, division wide production information reporting system (KPI's and real-time information), computerized systems for the atmospheric emissions reduction (AER) program, smelting converter aisle monitoring system, migration of Setcim data historian to OSISoft PI historian, applications using OSISoft technologies
- Product lead on SAP Manufacturing Integration and Intelligence (MII)

## Vale Canada Limited

2005-2009

# Process Systems Analyst

- Design, develop, test, deliver and support information and process control systems
- Implemented new technologies into business applications, business requirements analysis/translation
- Lead IT contractors and projects, served as mentor to colleagues

# **EDUCATION**

Georgian College (Diploma, 3 Year Computer Programmer/Analyst Co-op w/ Honours) 1999-2002 Lo-Ellen Park Secondary School (Ontario Secondary School Diploma w/Honours) 1994-1999

## LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

CompTIA Network+, CompTIA	02/2021
CompTIA Project+, CompTIA	09/2020
CompTIA PenTest+, CompTIA	09/2020
CompTIA Security+, CompTIA	08/2020
Effective Leadership Development, LMI Canada	03/2016